<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>posts on bojoism</title>
    <link>https://blog.bojo.wtf/categories/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in posts on bojoism</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.bojo.wtf/categories/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Note Taking</title>
      <link>https://blog.bojo.wtf/2020/06/04/efficient-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bojo.wtf/2020/06/04/efficient-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>Efficient Note Taking As my company starts belatedly revamping our corporate structure a lot of things have been changing, including my personal spiral towards a manager schedule vs a maker schedule lately. One thing I have noticed as I track more and more disparate things is that if I don&amp;rsquo;t start taking better notes now I&amp;rsquo;m going to fall behind and drown in forgotten caveats sooner than later. The less effective I am at tracking what I need to do (outside of task based work), or need to know across a breadth of projects, people, and responsibilities, the less effective I am going to be at supporting my team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From IC to EM</title>
      <link>https://blog.bojo.wtf/2020/04/05/from-ic-to-em/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bojo.wtf/2020/04/05/from-ic-to-em/</guid>
      <description>Intent My goal is to use this specific blog post to serve as both a starting point, and something I can refer to which describes the last three years of my career. Hopefully providing the reader with some context as to various decisions, cultural settings, and hurdles which helped define choices I have made and will make from here on out as I continue to add more content here.
As to why I have started a new blog in particular, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to come to terms with completely changing roles from an Individual Contributor (IC) to a Software Engineering Manager over these last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
